<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Jeffrey Moro</title>
 <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-09-13T23:39:11-04:00</updated>
 <id>https://jeffreymoro.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jeffrey Moro</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>These gigantic timescales are truly humiliating...</title>
   <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/09/13/these-gigantic-timescales/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/09/13/these-gigantic-timescales</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These gigantic timescales are truly humiliating in the sense that they force us to realize how close to Earth we are. Infinity is far easier to cope with. Infinity brings to mind our cognitive powers, which is why for Kant the mathematical sublime is the realization that infinity is an un- countably vast magnitude beyond magnitude. But hyperobjects are not forever. What they offer instead is very large finitude. I can think infinity. But I can’t count up to one hundred thousand. I have written one hundred thousand words, in fits and starts. But one hundred thousand years? It’s unimaginably vast. Yet there it is, staring me in the face, as the hyperobject global warming. And I helped cause it. I am directly responsible for beings that far into the future, insofar as two things will be true simultaneously: no one then will meaningfully be related to me; and my smallest action now will affect that time in profound ways. A Styrofoam cup will outlive me by over four hundred years. The plastic bag in Ramin Bahrani’s movie (in the voice of Werner Herzog) wishes to talk to the woman it knows as its maker, the woman who used it to carry her groceries: “If I could meet my maker, I would tell her just one thing: I wish that she had created me so that I could die.” To hear a plastic bag wish such a thing is profoundly different from thinking abstract infinity. There is a real sense in which it is far easier to conceive of “forever” than very large finitude. Forever makes you feel important. One hundred thousand years makes you wonder whether you can imagine one hun- dred thousand anything. It seems rather abstract to imagine that a book is one hundred thousand words long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Timothy Morton&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.upress.umn.edu/book-division/books/hyperobjects&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hyperobjects: Philosophy and Ecology After the End of the World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (University of Minnestota Press, 2013, this quote from pg. 60) is the closest I&amp;#39;ve gotten in a while to feeling like I&amp;#39;m in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kSnJl7B_TVs&amp;amp;noredirect=1&quot;&gt;Total Perspective Vortex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On seeing through Twitter</title>
   <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/09/02/on-seeing-through-Twitter/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/09/02/on-seeing-through-Twitter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On August 24th, Ars Technica reported that Twitter (the corporation) cut off API access to Twitter (the database) for a number of websites. These websites, &lt;a href=&quot;http://politwoops.sunlightfoundation.com&quot;&gt;Politwoops&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://diplotwoops.org&quot;&gt;Diplotwoops&lt;/a&gt;, were dedicated to archiving and displaying tweets that the official accounts of politicians, diplomats, and other governmental agencies tweeted and then deleted. &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/08/twitter-cuts-api-access-to-more-sites-archiving-deleted-politicians-tweets/&quot;&gt;From Ars’ article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has severed API access to more sites that archive deleted tweets from politicians. The most recent targets—Diplotwoops and the international version of Politwoops—spanned at least 30 countries, but Twitter found the sites to be in breach of the service’s privacy policy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend’s development comes three months after Twitter cut API access for the US’ political tweet watchdog, Politwoops, for the same reason. The Sunlight Foundation ran the US Politwoops, and the Open State Foundation ran 30 international versions of Politwoops in addition to Diplotwoops. Both organizations lashed out at this recent decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sites like Diplotwoops and Politwoops, API access is everything. An API (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Application_programming_interface&quot;&gt;application programming interface&lt;/a&gt;) is a kind of grammar, a set of instructions for interacting with a computing platform. The Twitter API and the permissions granted through its use were what powered these sites’ ability to access politicians’ live feeds, write tweets to a database, check for later deletions, and then post those deleted tweets to the public Internet. Twitter’s stated reason for shutting these services down was that they were in violation of the API’s terms of use, which &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/overview/terms/agreement-and-policy#3.Update_Respect_Users_Control_and_Privacy&quot;&gt;states that developers must&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Take all reasonable efforts to do the following, provided that when requested by Twitter, you must promptly take such actions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i. Delete Content that Twitter reports as deleted or expired;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ii. Change treatment of Content that Twitter reports is subject to changed sharing options (e.g., become protected); and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iii. Modify Content that Twitter reports has been modified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A straightforward enough case, right? However, as the Sunlight Foundation, the NGO that ran Politwoops, wrote on its blog when its API access was suspended, Twitter had contacted them about terms of use violations way back in 2012 and had reached an agreement with the Foundation to allow its website to operate unencumbered. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sunlightfoundation.com/blog/2015/06/04/eulogy-for-politwoops/&quot;&gt;To wit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days after Politwoops launched in 2012, Twitter contacted the Sunlight Foundation and told us, “Your service violates our API Terms of Service on a fundamental level.” We explained the goals of the project and agreed to create a human curation workflow to ensure that the site screened out corrected low-value tweets like typos, links and Twitter handles. We implemented this layer of journalistic judgment with blessings from Twitter and the site continued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changed between 2012 and 2015? There’s a feeling online, one that I’ve noticed in a number of channels but principally on Twitter, that something has changed, and not for the better. There’s a sense that surveillance, already a major part of our lives online, has expanded. There’s a sense of futility in the face of the “sharing economy,” as the trends instituted by comically evil corporations like Uber lock more of us in &lt;a href=&quot;http://platformcoop.net&quot;&gt;part-time, contingent labor&lt;/a&gt;. There’s a sense that social media has fulfilled its dark promise as &lt;a href=&quot;http://the-toast.net/2015/07/23/an-interview-with-sarah-jeong/&quot;&gt;a perfect tool for harassment&lt;/a&gt;, and women, people of color, people who speak up against the flow of garbage find themselves attacked and driven into protected accounts—or offline entirely. And there’s a sense that the Internet’s ability to amplify horrid events, to mobilize social activist movements like Arab Spring or Black Lives Matter, has a darker side: one that reifies and insists on witnessing trauma and injustice beyond a human’s capacity to withstand it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changed between 2012 and 2015? Trayvon Martin was murdered, Michael Brown was murdered, Renisha McBride was murdered. We had an election, are about to have another one. Twitter gained hundreds of thousands of users, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/08/twitter-global-social-media/402415/&quot;&gt;but they’re not talking&lt;/a&gt;. And the money gathers upward, like it always has. Our lives online feel increasingly mandatory, and increasingly exhausting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching Twitter (the corporation) pull the plug on sites like Diplotwoops and Politwoops teaches us what power is when social media networks are concerned. I want to use their example to kick off what I anticipate will be a series of blog posts about Twitter, our utterances on it, and our relationships to each other through it. I agree with those who think that the Internet, as we know and knew it, is at some kind of breaking point. Let’s dig through the rubble together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past month, I’ve been collaborating with Marisa Parham on the beginnings of a project called &lt;em&gt;Still Life in Digital: Black Life, Trauma, and Social Media&lt;/em&gt;. The project’s goal, as we envision it, is to push on the rhetoric of the digital making things, relationships, utterances, and lives floaty, disembodied, cloud-like. For Black life, we argue, it does the opposite. Social media overconcretizes lives in ways that bodies can’t sustain. Web Smith writes about this in a Medium post called &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@web/our-truth-is-why-twitter-is-struggling-ffc6a4e02bcd&quot;&gt;“Our Truth is Why Twitter is Struggling,”&lt;/a&gt; in which he says: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is suffering because it is the most accurate reflection of American society today. It’s not just what’s tweeted, it’s what isn’t tweeted. &lt;strong&gt;Each day, a new hashtag represents a dead child.&lt;/strong&gt; Often, there is a filmed murder attached. Often still, we watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dare I say, that Twitter’s problem is its ability to trigger us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Every death reminds us that, even if we’re perfect, we may die today. Every advocacy of an African lion reminds us that African-Americans are traditionally less important than animals. We watch what’s important to our friends and then ask, why is my friendship not important to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, we’ve been thinking about data visualization: how the graph, map, tree, or chart has gained prominence in the way we talk, write, and share online, and its role in making violence towards Black life constantly visible and explicable in ways that are both necessary and deleterious. It’s been my job over the past month to learn more about techniques for data visualization, how to turn corpuses of data, especially tweets, into compelling visual representations, and to think about what that process of representation entails. Our starting point was this striking heat map of tweets sent out during the week following Michael Brown’s shooting in Ferguson, MO: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#39;100%&#39; height=&#39;520&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; src=&#39;https://srogers.cartodb.com/viz/4a5eb582-23ed-11e4-bd6b-0e230854a1cb/embed_map&#39; allowfullscreen webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen oallowfullscreen msallowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are we seeing here? How are individual utterances, and the bodies that produced them, represented in a map like this? What &lt;em&gt;aren’t&lt;/em&gt; we seeing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly became obsessed with the data underneath, with understanding how someone would go about accessing the raw stream of tweets and metadata that powers this or any other visualization. To begin collect tweets for our project, I used the same free, open, public API that powered Diplotwoops and Politwoops. I have to admit, I was a little shocked at what I saw constituted a single tweet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one tweet—one of mine, taken from a few days ago: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot; data-lang=&quot;json&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;contributors&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;truncated&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;interesting reflection on who&amp;#39;s doing the talking and the listening and the ignoring on this website dot com: http://t.co/RVzTR7pDGM&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;is_quote_status&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;in_reply_to_status_id&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;636912109163520000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;favorite_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;source&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;lt;a href=\&amp;quot;http://twitter.com\&amp;quot; rel=\&amp;quot;nofollow\&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Twitter Web Client&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;retweeted&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;coordinates&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;entities&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;symbols&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;user_mentions&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;hashtags&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[],&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;urls&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://t.co/RVzTR7pDGM&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;indices&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;110&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;132&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;19&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;expanded_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2015/08/twitter-global-social-media/402415/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;display_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;theatlantic.com/international/\u2026&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;21&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;in_reply_to_screen_name&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;in_reply_to_user_id&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;23&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;retweet_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;24&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;id_str&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;636912109163520000&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;favorited&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;26&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;user&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;27&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;follow_request_sent&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;28&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;has_extended_profile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;29&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_use_background_image&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;default_profile_image&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;31&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1478357942&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;32&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_background_image_url_https&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://abs.twimg.com/images/themes/theme1/bg.png&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;33&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;verified&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;34&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_text_color&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;333333&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;35&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_image_url_https&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/611518361206423552/ICDpOPuK_normal.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;36&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_sidebar_fill_color&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;DDEEF6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;37&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;entities&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;38&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;39&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;urls&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;40&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://t.co/UuZFn8Zbva&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;41&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;indices&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;],&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;42&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;expanded_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://jeffreymoro.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;43&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;display_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;jeffreymoro.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;44&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;45&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;description&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;46&lt;/span&gt;                     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;urls&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[]}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;47&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;48&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;followers_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;173&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;49&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_sidebar_border_color&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;C0DEED&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;id_str&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;1478357942&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;51&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_background_color&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;C0DEED&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;52&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;listed_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;53&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;is_translation_enabled&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;54&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;utc_offset&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;10800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;55&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;statuses_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1636&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;56&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;description&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;electronic literature, media history, software studies // all-purpose post-bac for @5collDH // helps run @thecriticalis&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;57&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;friends_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;426&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;58&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;location&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Northampton, MA&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;59&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_link_color&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;0084B4&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_image_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/611518361206423552/ICDpOPuK_normal.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;61&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;following&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;62&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;geo_enabled&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;63&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_banner_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_banners/1478357942/1436916421&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;64&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_background_image_url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://abs.twimg.com/images/themes/theme1/bg.png&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;65&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;screen_name&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;jeffreymoro&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;66&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;lang&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;67&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;profile_background_tile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;68&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;favourites_count&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;405&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;69&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Jeffrey Moro&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;70&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;notifications&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;71&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://t.co/UuZFn8Zbva&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;72&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;created_at&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Sun Jun 02 22:34:06 +0000 2013&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;73&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;contributors_enabled&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;74&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;time_zone&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Athens&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;75&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;protected&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;76&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;default_profile&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;77&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;is_translator&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;78&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;79&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;geo&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;in_reply_to_user_id_str&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;81&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;possibly_sensitive&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;82&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;lang&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;83&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;created_at&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Thu Aug 27 14:44:14 +0000 2015&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;84&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;in_reply_to_status_id_str&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;85&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;place&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;86&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;metadata&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;87&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;iso_language_code&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;88&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;result_type&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;recent&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;89&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;90&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s overwhelming. It feels like &lt;a href=&quot;http://westwing.wikia.com/wiki/Take_Out_the_Trash_Day&quot;&gt;that episode of &lt;em&gt;The West Wing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; when, to bamboozle reporters who ask for internal documents from the President’s office, the Bartlet administration releases &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, drowning the press in paper. This 90-line .json is a single tweet. Try working with more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://inkdroid.org/2014/08/30/a-ferguson-twitter-archive/&quot;&gt;13 million of them&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these fields are self-explanatory, and after the initial shock dies down, make perfect sense from an architectural standpoint. The tweet’s text, its favorite count, whether it’s even been retweeted, geographic information: if you look at this document from the perspective of someone building a Twitter app, then everything becomes clear. I’m particularly interested in the “entities” field, which contains detailed information about all of the links &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; a single tweet. One tweet effectively contains the full metadata for all of its relationships, which allows one to map out webs of fractal connections. (If you’re getting a weird &lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt;-y whiff from all of this, I don’t think it’s unintentional.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at these streams of data, I realized that visualization is more than charts and graphs. Twitter, the web interface, is itself a visualization, in the sense that it’s a representation in dimensional space of a complex dataset. Twitter, the web interface, relies on visual rhetoric to communication information and produce effects in the same way any well-made chart would. It’s useful to distinguish Twitter-the-interface from Twitter-the-data (and also from Twitter-the-corporation). Doing so allows us to understand (and here the software engineers are perhaps a step ahead of the academics, in the sense that the former has a rich vocabulary of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service&quot;&gt;software/platform-as-a-service&lt;/a&gt; to understand this separation) what Twitter is doing when it pulls the plug on Politwoops or Diplotwoops: it’s implicitly claiming the value of one kind of visualization over another. The dataset is the same; it’s how you look at it that changes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our lives online are subject to a regime of sight, of web sites and services that use design techniques to surface information in specific ways. When Web Smith writes that Twitter&amp;#39;s problem is &amp;quot;its ability to trigger us,&amp;quot; this is what he means. We&amp;#39;re given things to see, and little control over how we see them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I wrote above, I imagine this post is the first in an intermittent series over the next few months, exploring visualizations that I end up making for this project, and digging deeper into questions of how lives and bodies, particularly Black lives and Black bodies, are construed online. If you’re interested in learning more about how the Twitter API works (I am so far from an expert that it’s comical I’m even writing this blog post), there’s ample documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.twitter.com&quot;&gt;dev.twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend going and looking at that site in any case, particularly if you’re a regular Twitter user. It’s useful to see how the services that we use construe themselves on the backend, especially when they diverge radically from how they’d like us to perceive their front-ends. It’ll also give you a sense of how you might go about harvesting tweets for your own use (man, these metaphors get creepy &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;), though I hope to write about those processes more soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Visualizing the New Rigor</title>
   <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/26/visualizing-the-new-rigor/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/26/visualizing-the-new-rigor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back in May, Five College Digital Humanities organized a conference called &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt;, in which we tackled the question of what kinds of support and evaluation structures would best facilitate making interesting, innovative digital work. The conference was a whole lot of fun, and if you&amp;#39;re interested in some of those conversations, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewrigor.org&quot;&gt;checking out the conference&amp;#39;s website&lt;/a&gt;, which has documentation and notes out the wazoo. I don&amp;#39;t want to talk about evaluating digital projects, though—I want to talk about making silly sproingy toys in Javascript. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;sproingcanvas&quot; class=&quot;canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a force-directed graph (named because it simulates physical forces, &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; sproinginess) represented all of the tweets sent out during &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt;, mostly between 1 PM and 1:45 PM on May 2nd, 2015. During the conference, we split participants up into color groups that more or less tracked their role in academia: red for undergraduates, orange for staff members, blue for graduate students, green for tenure-track faculty, and purple for tenured faculty. The colors of each of the nodes (those circles representing tweets) matches the tweeter&amp;#39;s color group. Hovering over the node displays the tweeter&amp;#39;s username, real name (well, their name that they go by on Twitter!) and the text of their tweet. Double-clicking any node highlights it and all nodes connected to it, and of course, you can drag the whole graph around like colorful Slinky. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this visualization using &lt;a href=&quot;http://d3js.org&quot;&gt;D3.js&lt;/a&gt;, a Javascript library for making (and I paraphrase from the explanations of D3 littered across the World Wide Web) flexible data-driven documents. Charts, graphs, &lt;a href=&quot;http://koalastothemax.com&quot;&gt;pixel toys that reveal koalas&lt;/a&gt;: if it&amp;#39;s made of data and visuals, D3&amp;#39;s got your back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/koalastothemax-comp.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;To the max!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as fun as sproingy data is, it doesn&amp;#39;t really tell us anything interesting about the tweets, other than eyeballing the number of tweets in each color group. The ostensible value of tweets is as a record of the day&amp;#39;s proceedings. How could we get a better sense of what &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&lt;/em&gt; was talking about, from a macro view?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;timelinecanvas&quot; class=&quot;canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, would you look at that! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a slice of all of the tweets, but it encapsulates the majority of all of the tweets tagged with particular color groups, which corresponds nicely to the conference&amp;#39;s primary breakout session. It&amp;#39;s interesting to see which groups tweeted the most (staff, in orange, are the runaway victors), as well as what themes emerged at different points of the conversation. The most common talking point, as I can see it, is the value of failure, and the challenge of learning how to articulate failure as a useful scholarly practice. This is something that I thought about frequently as I put together this blog post: i.e., the value of repeated (endlessly repeated) failure when trying to get embedded D3 to work in my posts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re interested in the full visualizations, you can check them out over on &lt;em&gt;The New Rigor&amp;#39;s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenewrigor.org&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, and if you want to see the source code, you can find that on my GitHub under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jeffreymoro/newrigor-viz&quot;&gt;newrigor-viz&lt;/a&gt; repo. I&amp;#39;m currently working on some wordclouds and tweet walls, and will write up another blog post once I get those up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/public/js/d3sproing.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;/public/js/newrigortimeline.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Amnesia</title>
   <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/20/on-amnesia/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/20/on-amnesia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a post that I wrote back in the fall of 2014 for &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaming.thecritical.is&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Critical Is&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When setting up this blog, this felt like as good a post as any to port over, given that 1) I&amp;#39;m proud of it and 2) the issues it raises have not gotten any better in the intervening year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder0&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When old technology all but disappears in the face of the new, how do we value remembering?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks of September, 2014 were a hard couple of weeks to play video games. Specifically, to play video games from any cultural position other than that of a straight, white, young, middle-class male. On some level, we know this already, and while I wish I could say that I’ve been surprised by the rampant, unmitigated vitriol, no longer “trending towards” but rather actively resorting to violent threats, against &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/&quot;&gt;Anita Sarkeesian since she posted the most recent video in her Tropes vs. Women in Video Games series&lt;/a&gt;, against &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/sep/01/how-to-attack-a-woman-who-works-in-video-games&quot;&gt;female developers and critics guilty of no crimes save daring to exist, let alone work in the games industry&lt;/a&gt;— but the sound has turned to noise. I remain disgusted, appalled, and enraged, but not surprised: we all know too well by now the history of a particular subset of gaming culture’s hostility to any perceived attacks on its “territory.” Even when these attacks are nothing more than daring to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt;. Prominent women, LGBT, or non-white developers and critics have been quite literally forced from their homes in online attacks that, in their organization, militancy, and ideology can only be described (I wish I were being hysterical, but I am not) as terrorism: this is, horrifically, business as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of ways to read these fraught, terrifying moments, and I’m thankful that gaming journalism, journalism in general, and individual bloggers have stepped up over the past few weeks to provide numerous sane, intelligent, and necessarily excoriating takes. I’ll link to some here, and more at the bottom of this essay. The bulk of these pieces have focused on the cultural side of things: Leigh Alexander, in &lt;em&gt;Gamasutra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/224400/Gamers_dont_have_to_be_your_audience_Gamers_are_over.php&quot;&gt;writes of how the sociological classification of “gamers” is dying off&lt;/a&gt;; in &lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/em&gt;, Joseph Bernstein &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/josephbernstein/gaming-is-leaving-gamers-behind#.meBXz3Ddd&quot;&gt;maps the synecdochic fallacy of “gamers” onto cinema&lt;/a&gt;; Ian Steadman in &lt;em&gt;The New Statesman&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newstatesman.com/future-proof/2014/08/tropes-vs-anita-sarkeesian-passing-anti-feminist-nonsense-critique&quot;&gt;eviscerates the supposed “critique” of Sarkeesian’s work from her violent detractors as “anti-feminist nonsense.”&lt;/a&gt; In essence, each essay describes the same anthropological moment: a subculture, confronted with obsolence, lashes out. It’s primal—a battle over perceived territory and relevance aided by the anonymity of social media and abetted by a long history of companies prizing or denigrating communities in the marketplace. “Real gamers are X,” went the marketing canard for well over a decade, “and never Y.” This historical relic collapses, as each of the aforementioned essays shows, in the face of today’s wide(r) variety of games and gamers. “Games,” as a monolithic cultural category encompassing only a narrow slice of experiences, fall apart; the &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt; center cannot hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m loath to simply this trajectory, though, or to frame it as inevitable that the stereotypical “gamers” (and we need a better name for this subculture, given that, as Bernstein shows, “gamers” is as specific and critically useful as “moviegoers”) will disappear, or assimilate peacefully. To do so not only obscures the fact htat the ongoing abuse and harrasment of subaltern voices in the games community will not simply stop over time, but requires, like any other attempt at social justice, solidarity, vigilance, and action. I’m worried, as well, about the ways that the current technological and economic superstructures of capital-VG Video Gaming as a medium actively restrict our collective abilities to maintain a kind of critical historical memory that can inform and sustain us against future injustice. We shouldn’t seek to overcome the strictures of our pasts only to turn around and erase them from our memory — and I’m concerned that the games industry itself (like any technology industry) is invested, has always been invested, on the level of hardware and code, in this kind of forgetting. Furthermore, our attempts at engaging with video games in thoughtful, critical, and reflexive ways—the kinds of ways that Sarkeesian seeks to engage with games—will continue to come up short when faced with these kinds of encoded amnesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By “forgetting,” in this context, I want to address what I see as twinned issues: first, the idea of an archive as central to any critical apparatus; and second, the ways that the games industry actively substitutes nostalgia for historicity, and in doing so, encourages the existence of the idea of a subculture of “gamers” (which, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HanFreakinSolo/status/507509617623302144&quot;&gt;as these tweets&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HanFreakinSolo/status/507509685222924288&quot;&gt;from games developer Patrick Lindsey&lt;/a&gt; point out, with no small amount of invective, that “gamer” is first and foremost a corporate identity) that perpetuates, on some level, this violence. These are broad issues that I’m interested in teasing out over future blog posts, so in the spirit of concision, I’d like to explore some of the technological and material issues at play here, and see how they link up to the economic and cultural apparatuses surrounding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder1&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First, let&amp;#39;s talk about backwards compatibility.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The games industry, like the technology industry as a whole, thrives on the idea of planned obsolescence. Apple is its king: it strategically makes key features exclusive to each subsequent iteration of iDevice in order to encourage you to upgrade as frequently as possible. In the games industry (and here I’m restricting my view, for a moment, to consoles), obsolescence works very simply: with each new console generation (Super Nintendo to Nintendo 64; Playstation 3 to PS4), you generally have to buy a whole new crop of games, and bury your old ones in the closet. Frequently, new games will be on entirely different physical formats — Blu Ray discs instead of DVD; radically different shaped cartridges — that send the obvious message, “You can’t fit us into that new box.” It works on the level of software, too, through iterative series like &lt;em&gt;Mario Kart&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;FIFA&lt;/em&gt;. With each passing year, we usher in the new and force out the old: this, we have accepted, is the tidal churn of progress. You can &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; this progress, as a consumer, in the physical shape and composition of the media containers themselves. To take the progression of my own childhood into account, there was something compelling about seeing the boxy edges of the Super Nintendo’s cartridges round off for the N64, before eventually moving to discs (a real sign of technological progress — the kids across the street, who were a Playstation family, had had discs for years!). The physical media educates the consumer to relate to her games as ephemeral, as soon-to-be-superceded, as imminently obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backwards compatibility works against this churn. It’s the basic idea that the software of the past be executable by the hardware of the present. It’s the expectation that my less-powerful games that I bought last year can be played on my more-powerful console I buy next year. It makes logical sense: obviously, I can’t play new games on old hardware because of Progress, but why can’t I play old games on my new, shiny system? After all, I paid for them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the console industry isn’t a huge fan, given that planned obsolescence can make a positive impact on revenue. Moreover, given how (and Hollywood has co-opted this view in recent years) major publishers’ profits in recent years are dependent on major tent-pole releases in “evergreen” series like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt;, there’s a present drive to convince the consumer that she needs to purchase the newest iteration, that all of the old iterations were incomplete compared this, this newest one. For these reasons and more, backwards compatibility has been traditionally altogether absent on consoles, although it thrived on Nintendo’s handheld Gameboy and DS platforms, where the previous generation of games was always playable on the current hardware (one imagines for marketing reasons as much as Nintendo’s particular niche in the industry as a purveryor of nostalgia), though revisions of each piece of hardware eventually excised these features as well, ostensibly in the name of portability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a two-fold effect this had on me as a child, and, honestly, continues to have on me as an adult. The first is a kind of frustration coupled with resignation coupled with consumerist delight as I swipe my card every four years or so — a familiar feeling, now, to anyone who owns a smartphone. In a way, this feeling of being forced, by the hand of industry, to dispose of last year’s possessions has been normalized by Apple, Samsung, et al. — as video games have reached a broader audience, frequently through the smartphone as a platform, so too have its industry’s obsolescence strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is an urge to collect, to store, to have a physical memory of systems past. I’ve made it a point to hold onto most of the systems and games of my childhood, for two reasons: first, because I still find the games fun to play; and second, because of a twinned feeling of nostalgia for the past and anxiety that the past will someday disappear, that the software will stop running, that the hardware will break down, and I’ll be left with the shell of a talisman, unable to summon the spirit. This is already happening to some of my games. &lt;em&gt;Pokémon&lt;/em&gt; fans of a certain age and a certain temperament will recognize the moment you put in an old cartridge, say, from 1998 or so, and found that the game would run fine, but would not save, because the small battery burrowed away in each cartridge had finally run out. You can replace that battery, sure, with solder and gumption, but it’s a concrete object lesson in the impermanence and entropy of all physical systems. How long until the battery runs out again? How long will you keep replacing it? When do you decide your memory is enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can understand, on some level, the territoriality this inspires in fans of this, or perhaps any computational media. It evokes a fascination with a very specific kind of past — imagined to be your own past — and fetishizes it as imminently on the verge of erasure. Because, in the context of the market, it is. Games publishers have begun to realize this in recent years, and have increasingly made very specific games from the past available for contemporary consumers, generally in the form of an HD re-release (akin to a remaster, and always changing some key pieces of the game, whether upgrading graphics or changing key gameplay) or, as Nintendo and Sony have done with the Virtual Console and Playstation Plus, respectively, developing digital store-fronts through which consumers can (re)purchase old games to play in emulation on their current systems. (No word, though, on whether or not these games will be portable to future systems, or how many times consumers will have to re-purchase what is in essence their own, personal archive.) In independent games development, “retro” has become an aesthetic, code for punishingly difficult platformers with blocky, 8-bit graphics. It’s the memory of a very particular demographic, useful to those selling the games, but not particularly useful to those playing them, or writing about them, or even making them. All it does is allow the monolithic corporations of the games industry — not even the smaller developers on the ground, many of whom are doing genuinely interesting, innovative work — to control the terms of their own histories, to map the terrain of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;amnesiaborder2&quot; class=&quot;bleed&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The obvious answer might be developing robust games archives.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a revolutionary claim by any means, and many spaces within and outside academia, like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gamecenter.nyu.edu&quot;&gt;NYU Game Center&lt;/a&gt;, the MoMA’s new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moma.org/explore/inside_out/2013/06/28/video-games-seven-more-building-blocks-in-momas-collection&quot;&gt;video games collection&lt;/a&gt;, UC-Boulder’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediaarchaeologylab.com&quot;&gt;Media Archaeology Lab&lt;/a&gt;, the Internet Archive’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/consolelivingroom&quot;&gt;Console Living Room&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jsmess/jsmess&quot;&gt;JSMESS emulator&lt;/a&gt; are taking incredible steps towards a future of critical gaming. The archive is an attractive solution, particularly for games and technology more generally, given the complex technical and logistical requirements of born-digital media preservation. It’s the uphill battle of digital media, in that there’s always more and more &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;, and it all requires exacting, particular systems to get it right, whether its figuring out the logistics of a collection of physical hardware and media, or working out the precise systems that go into &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2011/08/accuracy-takes-power-one-mans-3ghz-quest-to-build-a-perfect-snes-emulator/&quot;&gt;emulating software&lt;/a&gt;. None of what I’ve pointed out above begins to grapple with the large community of indie developers working on platforms like Twine, or what to do with all of the games from the 2000s that were written in soon-to-be-obsolete Flash. (Although, for thoughts on that issue, you might want to check out Zach Whalen’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zachwhalen.net/posts/lexia-to-perplexia-2000-2013/&quot;&gt;talk from MLA 2013&lt;/a&gt; on the seminal, though now un-executable, piece of electronic literature, Talan Memmott’s Lexia to Perplexia.) The attractiveness of “build archives” as a solution is that it makes all of these questions, on some level, somebody’s else’s problem — someone with The Skills, The Knowledge, and, most importantly, The Time. We need to reconfigure (or at least, take a fresh look at) our relationship to electronic media, to the open-source and proprietary systems we use to create and execute that media, and to our relationship with the larger economic interests that, at practically every level, manage and condition these relationships. I’m not calling for the End Of All Games Corporations. I might be calling for the End Of Games Corporations As Their Own Historians, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something insidious about asking (allowing!) games publishers to be their own archivists. Doing so denies players and critics access to a more-complete picture of gaming history. Like so many of the larger questions of sexism in the technology industry (think of Ubisoft’s claim that it couldn’t find resources to program and design a female protagonist in the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed: Unity&lt;/em&gt; because of budgetary limitations), it cloaks a sociological problem as an engineering problem, as if framing it all in questions of numbers and code would absolve publishers of a humanistic, moral, and cultural reckoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post’s title is partially misleading. There is nothing, arguably, about the medium of gaming (understood as an abstraction) that predestines historical amnesia. We don’t have to have computing systems, on some level, predicated on erasing the past with each forward step — and turning on that erasure more and more frequently with each passing year. Maybe that would slow down progress, or make innovation more difficult. I don’t pretend to have the breadth of technological knowledge and experience necessary to determine that. But looking at the past few weeks (months, years, decades) of rage, violence, and injustice, I don’t know if slowing down and cultivating a better sense of the fullness of our past would be such a terrible thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This is a blog post</title>
   <link href="https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/18/this-is-a-blog-post/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://jeffreymoro.com/2015/08/18/this-is-a-blog-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! This my blog, and this is a blog post. Welcome: I brought snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to see what a paragraph looks like on my new blog? Here you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can put that paragraph in block quotes, too: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also figured out how to include sweet, sweet code: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;tabsWrapper clear&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;id=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;t0&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;tabs&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;EDUCATION&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t2&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;EMPLOYMENT HISTORY&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t3&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;AWARDS + FELLOWSHIPS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t4&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;SCHOLARY + CREATIVE PROJECTS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t5&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;PUBLIC PRESENTATIONS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;14&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;COURSES + WORKSHOPS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;15&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;16&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#t7&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;SKILLS&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;17&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;18&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t anticipate using that one that much, although it does make me feel &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; cool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay: that&amp;#39;s it for now! Look at me, blogging. I never thought the day would come. Did you read down all the way to here expecting to learn something? Good: I wouldn&amp;#39;t want you to think that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
